Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations Mixed Heritage Oral History Project 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Vilray Bolles 2011.019.017, 1985-2012; 2011.019.017
  In his interview, Bolles discusses his experience growing up and going to school in Brooklyn and at LaGuardia for jazz music. He also talks about his brother’s connection to Islam, memories of going to church with his family, his connection to music, and the immigrant experience.
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Vilray Bolles, 1985-2012
    1 hour 24 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Vilray Bolles, 1985-2012
    31 pages
- Fikre Workneh 2011.019.018, 1937-2012; 2011.019.018
  Fikre Workneh is from Ethiopia and grew up in the Ethiopian Orthodox Church. Before marrying Clare Workneh, he worked as a chaplain and missionary.
  In his interview, Fikre discusses his upbringing in the Ethipoian Orthodox Church and his experience as a missionary and chaplain in the church. He talks about moving to the United States and serving the church in Harlem as well as his meeting and marriage to his wife Clare.
  Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Christianity; Ethiopians United States; Interracial dating; Interracial marriage; Racially mixed people
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Fikre Workneh, 1937-2012
    1 hour 31 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Fikre Workneh, 1985-2012
    33 pages
- Clare Workneh 2011.019.019, 1937-2012; 2011.019.019
  Christian life |z New York (State) |z New York; Convents |z New York (state); Interfaith families; Interfaith marriage; Interracial marriage; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Motherhood
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Clare Workneh, 1937-2012
    58 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (trancsript) with Clare Workneh, 1937-2012
    28 pages
- Clare and Fikre Workneh 2011.019.020, 1937-2012; 2011.019.020
  Clare Workneh was born in Brooklyn and grew up in Queens, New York. She worked as a nun and later as a social worker. She married Fikre Workneh in 1974.
  In her interview, Clare Workneh talks about her memories of the convent, her Irish background, her father converting to Catholicism when he met her mother and ethnic difference.
  Catholics |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Christianity; Interracial dating; Interracial marriage; Motherhood
  - Oral History Inteview (audio) with Clare and Fikre Workneh, 1937-2012
    34 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Clare and Fikre Workneh, 1937-2012
    19 pages
- Bette Yee 2011.019.021, 1949-2012; 2011.019.021
  Bette Yee is of Chinese descent and was born in Boston, Massachusetts. Yee also grew up in New Hampshire, where her family had a restaurant called China Dragon Inn. Yee attended the University of New Hampshire and moved to Brooklyn in the 1980s.
  In this interview, Yee talks about moving to New Hampshire from Boston and living with her uncle who was married to a French Canadian woman. She discusses what it was like to grow up between two worlds – between her Chinese family and American society. She also describes her experience with the civil rights movements, her marriage, moving to Brooklyn in the 1980s and her exposure to the Asian American feminist movement, and her family’s disapproval of her own wedding.
  Acculturation; Chinese Americans; Cooking; Families; Food |x Social aspects; Holidays |z New York (State); Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z New York; United States |x Emigration and immigration
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Bette Yee, 1949-2012
    2 hours 32 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Better Yee, 1949-2012
    55 pages
- Jonathan Blazon 2011.019.022, 1969-2012; 2011.019.022
  Jonathan Blazon was born in Manchester, New Hampshire. He is of Chinese, French-Canadian, and American Indian descent and identifies as Hapa. He lived in Brooklyn before and after spending ten years studying in France. Jonathan has a Master's degree in Fine Arts. His mother, Bette Yee, was also interviewed for this project.
  In this interview, Blazon describes what it was like to grow up Hapa in New Hampshire. He talks about being bullied and never being seen as Chinese despite identifying more with his Chinese heritage than his French Canadian background. Blazon discusses life in his family’s restaurant in New Hampshire. He talks about living in France for ten years and what it was like to return to Brooklyn where he noticed significant changes in the attitude toward and understanding of mixed heritage people. He thinks about how his own feelings of being Hapa will affect his daughter.
  Chinese Americans; Ethnicity; Family life; France; Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Travel
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Jonathan Blazon, 1969-2012
    1 hour 16 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Jonathan Blazon, 1969-2012
- Vilray Bolles 2011.019.023, 1985-2012
  In this interview Vilray Bolles describes his life in Brooklyn since he graduated from college and his views on gentrification in the neighborhood of Park Slope, in which he grew up in.
  Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Musicians; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racism |z New York (State) |z New York; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Vilray Bolles, 1985-2012
    1 hour 54 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Vilray Bolles, 1985-2012
    84 pages
- Elizabeth Velazquez 2011.019.024, 1977-2012; 2011.019.024
  Elizabeth Velazquez was raised in Sullivan County in upstate New York. As the daughter of two immigrants (a Puerto Rican father and a Peruvian mother), Velazquez feels connected to the students in her Art classes at PS 89, Cypress Hills Community School, which is a bilingual school predominantly comprised of students of Latin American backgrounds. Velazquez is dedicated to learning more about her background and her family history, which are themes that often arise in her personal art practice.
  During this interview, which was conducted in Velazquez's art studio, Velazquez discusses her ongoing quest for knowledge, what she refers to as a lost history, in order to feel a greater connection to the past. She discusses feeling lost and never fitting in, whether in the US, in Puerto Rico, or in Peru, while feeling connected to her students in Brooklyn, who come from similar backgrounds.
  Growing up in upstate NY, Velazquez remembers looking around in her classes to identify someone else like her. She reflects on being raised Pentacostal, and feeling grateful for experiencing the food and music of other Latin American and Caribbean church members. She also discusses observing her father building and fixing things, which she later understood as a reflection of Puerto Rican history in her dad, who she views as an embodiment of where he grew up. As an adult, Velazquez seeks to fill the loss of ancestral knowledge, which she admits often results in anger mixed with a feeling of wanting to be at peace, which she compares to fighting a phantom.
  Acculturation; Art; Art schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Community development |z New York (State) |z New York; Ethnicity; Holidays |z New York (State)
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Elizabeth Velazquez, 1977-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Elizabeth Velazquez, 1977-2012
- Mala and Sham Mosher 2011.019.025, 1968-2012; 2011.019.025
  Mala is of Chinese and Burmese descent and grew up in New York City. Sham is from Washington, D.C.. His mother is black and his father is white and he grew up Sikh. Mala and Sham met in 1988 and their first apartment was in Brooklyn.
  In this interview, Mala and Sham Mosher talk about their own upbringings and their family ancestry. They talk about their relationship and how it was perceived by their own families.
  Burmese Americans; Chinese Americans; Interfaith marriage; Interracial dating; Interracial marriage; Sikh Americans; Washington (D.C.)
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Mala and Sham Mosher, 1968-2012
    1 hour 48 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Mala and Sham Mosher, 1968-2012
    45 pages
- Vanessa Snowden and Sebastien Fargeat 2011.019.026, 1980-2012
  Vanessa Snowden’s mother hails from Venezuela and her father grew up in the US. Sebastien Fargeat is from Lyon, France originally. They met when Snowden was working as an au pair in France. She is currently a teacher in the New York City Schools; he leads sightseeing expeditions for French tourists.
  In this interview, Snowden and Fargeat discusses their upbringings in Buffalo, NY and Lyon, France. Snowden talks about experiences in education growing up and as a teacher. Both talk about how they met and relate stories about their wedding and moving back to the US.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Family life; France; Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z New York; Multiculturalism; New York (N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration; New York (State); Weddings
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Vanessa Snowden and Sebastien Fargeat, 1980-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Vanessa Snowden and Sebastien Fargeat, 1980-2012
    52 pages
- Alicia Piller 2011.019.027, 1982-2012
  In her second interview, Piller talks about her education and what it was like to live in Chicago, Illinois as compared to Brooklyn, New York with respect to her background and identity.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Chicago (Ill.); Interfaith families; Interfaith marriage; Interracial dating; Interracial marriage
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Alicia Piller, 1982-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Alicia Piller, 1982-2012
- Justice Whitaker 2011.019.028, 1981-2012
  Justice Whitaker grew up in California. His mother is white and his father is black. He currently lives in Brooklyn and works as an artist.
  In his interview, Justice Whitaker talks about growing up in California, his encounters with racism, how his parents’ backgrounds influenced his life, and moving to New York City for college.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; California; College students |z New York (State) |z New York; Interracial marriage; Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z New York; Racism |z New York (State) |z New York
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Justice Whitaker, 1981-2012
    1 hour 46 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Justice Whitaker, 1981-2012
    47 pages
- Melissa Jimenez 2011.019.029, 1978-2012
  Melissa Jimenez is of Filipino and Dominican descent. She was very close with her grandmother from the Philippines.
  In her interview, Melissa Jimenez talks about her upbringing in a mixed family and the challenges of having two families close by that spoke different languages. She also talks about going to Chinatown with her grandmother and her daughter.
  Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Dominican Americans; Filipino Americans; Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Language and languages; Spanish language
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Melissa Jimenez, 1978-2012
    1 hour 26 minutes
    Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Dominican Americans; Filipino Americans; Language and languages; Spanish language
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Melissa Jimenez, 1978-2012
- Justice Whitaker 2011.019.030, 1981-2012
  In his second interview, Justice Whitaker talks about moving to New York City for college, the influence of film and music in his life, American politics, travel, and his own work.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Interracial dating; Mass media and ethnic relations; Racially mixed people; Racism |z New York (State) |z New York; Travel; Universities and colleges |z New York (State)
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Justice Whitaker, 1981-2012
    2 hours 45 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Justice Whitaker, 1981-2012
    65 pages
- Jessica Chen Drammeh 2011.019.031, Circa 1970-2012
  Jessica Chen Drammeh grew up in West Virginia with her Taiwanese mother and white father. She grew up speaking Chinese and English. She has lived in many neighborhoods in Brooklyn and works as filmmaker.
  In her interview, Jessica Chen Drammeh talks about her relationship with her parents and extended family, her experience in school and her family’s language practices. She talks about moving to New York City for college and the influence of arts and music on her life, as well as her career as a filmmaker.
  Chinese language; College students |z New York (State) |z New York; Language and languages; Mass media and ethnic relations; Taiwanese Americans
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Jessica Chen Drammeh, Circa 1970-2012
    1 hour 20 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Jessica Chen Drammeh, Circa 1970-2012
    35 pages
- Lowell Pete Beveridge 2011.019.032, 1930-2012
  Lowell Pete Beveridge has lived in Brooklyn since 1954 and was born in Massachusetts. He studied history at Harvard and Columbia and later married an African American woman from Harlem. He was involved in many political activities throughout his life.
  In his interview he talks about his upbringing in New York and summers in Maine, his background in history, American politics and his wife.
  Authors, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Interracial dating; Interracial marriage; Press and politics
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Lowell Pete Beveridge, 1930-2012
    2 hours 15 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Lowell Pete Beveridge, 1930-2012
- Ari Joseph 2011.019.033, 1982-2012
  Ari Joseph grew up in Park Slope, Brooklyn and attended LaGuardia High School of Music and Art where he studied music. His father is white and Jewish and his mother is Peruvian and Chinese.
  In his interview, Ari Joseph talks about what Brooklyn means to him and how it has changed over time. He also talks about what being “international” means to him, his education, and his relationship to music and Judaism.
  Chinese Americans; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; International relations; Judaism; Mass media and ethnic relations; Musicians; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Peruvian American
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Ari Joseph, 1982-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Ari Joseph, 1982-2012
    57 pages
- Hansraj Maharawal 2011.019.034, 1985-2012
  Hansraj Maharawal grew up in Park Slope and Prospect Heights, Brooklyn and attended Sarah Lawrence College. He currently works as a production assistant on photo shoots and is an artist. His mother is from New Jersey and is Scottish and his father is from India.
  In his interview, Maharawal is interviewed by his sister Mannissa McCleave Maharawal. In it, he talks about his friendships growing up in Brooklyn and what has changed about the borough since he was a child. He also talks about racism, whiteness, hipster culture, and the art world.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; East Indian Americans; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Mass media and ethnic relations; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Popular culture |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racism |z New York (State) |z New York; White privilege
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Hansraj Maharawal, 1985-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Hansraj Maharawal, 1985-2012
    56 pages
- Shawnta Smith 2011.019.035, 1983-2012
  Shawnta Smith was born and raised in East Flatbush, Brooklyn to a Jamaica-born father and a black mother whose parents were Gatemalan/Garifuna. She currently works as a librarian and archivist.
  In her interview, Shawnta Smith discusses growing up on “the sunny side of Brooklyn” a few blocks where she lives today. She talks about her education in an area where race and class differed greatly from place to place. She talks about her family structures, her values, and her work in queer organizing, activism, performance, and production.
  African Americans; African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Caribbean Americans; Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Community activists; Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York; Sexuality & culture
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Shawnta Smith, 1983-2012
    2 hours 54 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Shawnta Smith, 1983-2012
- Thomas Lax 2011.019.036, 1984-2012
  Thomas Lax grew up on the Upper West Side of Manhattan, New York. His mother is African-American and French and his father is Jewish-American. Lax received his BA in Africana Studies at Brown University where he did a year abroad in Dakar, Senegal. He currently works as an exhibition coordinator and program associate and lives in Brooklyn.
  In his interview, Thomas Lax tells stories about race and race relations, sexuality, religion and ethnicity that span generations and continents. He talks about how these stories relate to his own identity and how that identity has changed over time.
  African Americans; Group identity; Identity politics; Jews |z New York (State) |z New York; Museums; Religion; Sexuality & culture
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Thomas Lax, 1984-2012
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Thomas Lax, 1984-2012
    61 pages
- Joseph Figueroa 2011.019.037, 1977-2012
  Joseph Figueroa is a native Brooklynite of Puerto Rican and descent. He currently works in the community with at risk youth.
  In his interview, Joseph talks about growing up in Brownsville, Brooklyn, a predominately African American neighborhood in Brooklyn. He also explains his community work and how he is able to connect with and help youth today.
  Acculturation; African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Cultural pluralism; Gangs; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Economic conditions
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Joseph Figueroa, 1977-2012
    56 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Joseph Figueroa, 1977-2012
    23 pages
- Daisy Dominguez 2011.019.038, 1975-2012
  Daisy Dominguez is a first generation Ecuadorian-American who lived in Brooklyn for part of her childhood. She is a librarian at City College and has now returned to Brooklyn.
  In this interview, Dominguez talks about her experience growing up in Bushwick and how she was often perceived as Latina and not Ecuadorian. She talks about her relationship with her family and getting in touch with her Ecuadorian roots, where she moved to teach.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century; Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Ecuadorian Americans; Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Interracial dating; Multiculturalism
  - Oral History Interview (audio) with Daisy Dominguez, 1975-2012
    55 minutes
  - Oral History Interview (transcript) with Daisy Dominguez, 1975-2012